<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BIOBLU - BIOLOGY TEACHER FOR BLIND USERS</string>

    //string da classe main
    <string name="main_menu_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="main_menu_2">MENDEL´1S 1ST LAW</string>
    <string name="main_menu_3">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="main_menu_4">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>
    <string name="main_menu_5">Welcome to BIOBLU you are on the main menu. To navigate through options swipe up or down. A double tap allows you to choose an option.</string>
    <string name="main_menu_6">If you want to close the BIOBLU App Press and hold on the screen for two seconds. If you don\'t want to close, slide up or down to continue browsing!</string>
    <string name="main_menu_7">"Wrong Move"</string>

    //string da classe voice rate
    <string name="congifuracao_0">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_1">This is the Voice Speed Choice Menu. In it you will have 3 options to choose, You can navigate through the slide up or down after hearing the chosen option, make a double-tap to proceed.</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_2">Voice speed 1</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_3">Voice speed 2</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_4">Voice speed 3</string>

    //string tutorial main menu
    <string name="tutorial_1">You are in the environment screen here you learn how to use the navigation mechanisms within the application to return to the previous menu, just make an L in reverse at any time to begin, you must use the application menus. is very simple, just slide your finger anywhere on the screen and wait for the audio to return from the option where you find it. let\'s do it. slide your finger anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_2">To navigate between options, swipe up or down</string>
    <string name="tutorial_3">To confirm a chosen move or option, double-tap simultaneously</string>
    <string name="tutorial_4">To return to the previous screen, perform the movement of L in reverse</string>
    <string name="tutorial_5">To request help on the issue resolution screen, press and hold anywhere on the screen for 2 seconds</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6">To stop the audio, bring your hand in front of your smartphone screen</string>

    //string conceitos
    <string name="conceito_1">Gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_2">Genotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_3">Phenotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_4">Heterozygote</string>
    <string name="conceito_5">Homozygous</string>
    <string name="conceito_6">Dominant</string>
    <string name="conceito_7">Recessive</string>
    <string name="conceito_8">Codominance</string>
    <string name="conceito_9">Allele</string>
    <string name="conceito_10">Gametes</string>
    <string name="conceito_11">Dihybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_12">Monohybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_13">You are in the concept screen to navigate through them just swipe up or down, to return to the menu, make an reverse  L anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="conceito_14">Gene, Are specific sequences of nucleotides in DNA that constitute the fundamental unit of heredity.</string>
    <string name="conceito_15">Genotype, Group of genes of the individual.</string>
    <string name="conceito_16">Phenotype, Group of physical and physiological characteristics of an individual that results of the expression of the model and action of the environment.</string>
    <string name="conceito_17">Heterozygote, When an individual has two different alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_18">Homozygous, When an individual has two equal alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_19">Dominant, The allele is expressed in a homozygous condition and in a heterozygous condition</string>
    <string name="conceito_20">Recessive, The allele is only expressed in homozygosis for that reason it has no phenotypic effect when in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_21">Codominance, Situation in which the expression of the phenotypes of both alleles is observed when presented in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_22">Allele, alternative form of a gene that affects the same characteristic differently.</string>
    <string name="conceito_23">Gametes, are cells involved in sexual reproduction Heredity: transmission of resources from parents to their descendants.</string>
    <string name="conceito_24">Dihybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s second law, where differences in one characteristic are inherited regardless of differences in another characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_25">Monohybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s first law, and applies to hybrid individuals, considering only one characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_0">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>

    //string da classe cruzamento
    <string name="cruzamento_1">Now you are in the crossing screen. Make 4 taps to inform the Application which crossing you will make. After that, swipe 8 times to make the crossing you informed above</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_2">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_3">Gene </string>
    <string name="cruzamento_4">Homozygous Dominant Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_5">Heterozygous Dominant Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_6">Homozygous Recessive Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_7">You got it right !!! Continue.</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_8">The Genes generated through the Crossings were</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_9">Homozygote Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_10">Heterozygous Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_11">Homozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_12">Heterozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_13">Homozygote Recessive Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_14">Dominant</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_15">Recessive</string>

    //string da classe erro
    <string name="erro_1">BACK TO MENU</string>
    <string name="erro_2">Sorry, but we could not find any questions with your ID or you are not connected to the internet. To return to the menu, navigate to the option return to the menu and select</string>

    //string da classe seleção de letra
    <string name="selecao_0">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="selecao_1">You are  at Letter selection screen for the crossing. after choosing the desired option with the swipe up or down, double-tap to select the letter.</string>
    <string name="selecao_2">A</string>
    <string name="selecao_3">D</string>
    <string name="selecao_4">V</string>

    //string da classe select questão
    <string name="select_questao_0">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="select_questao_00">You are in the question selection screen. after choosing the desired option with the swipe up or down, double-tap to select the question</string>
    <string name="select_questao_1">Question 1</string>
    <string name="select_questao_2">Question 2</string>
    <string name="select_questao_3">Question 3</string>
    <string name="select_questao_4">Question 4</string>
    <string name="select_questao_5">Question 5</string>
    <string name="select_questao_6">We know that albinism is a recessive genetic anomaly in which the individual has a deficiency in the production of melanin in their skin, If a boy who produces melanin normally, but has a brother who is albine, ( Heterozygous Dominant), marries an albino girl, (Homozygous Recessive), What is the cross between this couple? </string>
    <string name="select_questao_7">Since myopia is considered a recessive disease, determine the crossing of a normal heterozygous couple for myopia</string>
    <string name="select_questao_8">What is the crossing generated by a couple, that both are heterozygous?</string>
    <string name="select_questao_9">A man who has dark eyes but with a mother with light eyes, married a woman with light eyes whose father has dark-eyed parents. Determine this crossing</string>
    <string name="select_questao_10">Achondroplasia is a type of dwarfism in which the head and trunk are normal, but the arms and legs are very short, It is conditioned by a dominant gene that, in homozygosity, causes death before birth. Normal individuals are recessive and the affected ones are heterozygous. What is this crossing?</string>

    //string da classe menu
    <string name="menu_1">TUTORIAL</string>
    <string name="menu_2">CRUZAMENTO</string>
    <string name="menu_3">QUESTÕES</string>
    <string name="menu_4">BUSCAR QUESTÕES</string>
    <string name="menu_5">Você está no módulo da primeira lei de mendel. você pode escolher a opção desejada deslizando na tela</string>
    <string name="menu_6">LEI DE MENDEL</string>

    //string da classe Questao
    <string name="questao_1">Confirmado Gene</string>
    <string name="questao_2">Gene Homozigoto Dominate</string>
    <string name="questao_3">Gene Heterozigoto Dominate</string>
    <string name="questao_4">Gene Homozigoto Recessivo</string>
    <string name="questao_5">Você acertou!!! Continue</string>
    <string name="questao_6">O Gene Informado Homozigoto Dominate está errado, tente novamente</string>
    <string name="questao_7">O Gene Informado Heterozigoto Dominate está errado, tente novamente</string>
    <string name="questao_8">O Gene Informado Homozigoto Recessivo está errado, tente novamente</string>
    <string name="questao_9">O Cruzamento está, Correto. Os Genes gerados através do Cruzamentos foram</string>
    <string name="questao_10">Porcento Homozigoto Dominante e</string>
    <string name="questao_11">Porcento Heterozigoto Dominante e</string>
    <string name="questao_12">Porcento Homozigoto Dominante</string>
    <string name="questao_13">Porcento Heterozigoto Dominante</string>
    <string name="questao_14">Porcento Homozigoto Recessivo</string>
    <string name="questao_15">para retornar ao menu, faça um L ao contrário em qualquer parte da tela</string>
    <string name="questao_16">O gene dominante é aquele que determina uma característica, já o recessivo só se expressa quando duplicado, isso porque quando há um dominante, ele se torna inativo</string>
    <string name="questao_17">Sabemos que o albinismo é uma anomalia genética recessiva em que o indivíduo portador apresenta uma deficiência na produção de melanina em sua pele Se um rapaz que produz melanina normalmente, mas tem um irmão que é albino,(Heterozigoto Domintate), se casa com uma menina albina,  (Homozigoto Recessivo), Qual é o  cruzamento entre  esse  casal?</string>
    <string name="questao_18">Visto que, o casal é heterozigoto e a miopia tem características recessivas, sabemos que seu alelo está presente nos dois pares de cromossomos</string>
    <string name="questao_19">Tendo em vista que a miopia é considerada uma doença recessiva determine o cruzamento de um casal normal heterozigoto para miopia.</string>
    <string name="questao_20">Heterozigotos representam os indivíduos de genes alelos diferentes, um dominante e um recessivo.</string>
    <string name="questao_21">Qual é o cruzamento gerado por um casal, que os dois são heterozigoto?</string>
    <string name="questao_22">A cor de olhos escuros é dominante sobre os olhos claros, que é recessivo</string>
    <string name="questao_23">um homem que possua os olhos escuros mas com a mãe de olhos claros, casou-se com uma mulher de olhos claros cujo pai possui pais dos olhos escuros. Determine esse cruzamento</string>
    <string name="questao_24">Se o gene apresentar características Homozigóticas Dominante, o feto morre, se for heterozigoto dominante, a criança nasce com a condição genética</string>
    <string name="questao_25">A acondroplasia é um tipo de nanismo em que a cabeça e o tronco são normais, mas braços e pernas são muito curtos É condicionado por um gene dominante que, em homozigose, provoca a morte antes do nascimento Os indivíduos normais são recessivos e os afetados são heterozigotos. Qual é esse cruzamento?</string>
    <string name="questao_26">Gene A Dominate, dê dois toques para confirmar</string>
    <string name="questao_27">Gene A recessivo, dê dois toques para confirmar</string>
    <string name="questao_28">Dominante</string>
    <string name="questao_29">Recessivo</string>



</resources>
