<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BIOBLU - BIOLOGY TEACHER FOR BLIND USERS</string>

    //string da classe main
    <string name="main_menu_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="main_menu_2">MENDEL´1S 1ST LAW</string>
    <string name="main_menu_3">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="main_menu_4">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>
    <string name="main_menu_5">Welcome to BIOBLU you are on the main menu. To navigate through options swipe up or down. A double tap allows you to choose an option.</string>
    <string name="main_menu_6">If you want to close the BIOBLU App Press and hold on the screen for two seconds. If you don\'t want to close, slide up or down to continue browsing!</string>
    <string name="main_menu_7">"Wrong Move"</string>

    //string da classe voice rate
    <string name="congifuracao_0">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_1">This is the Voice Speed Choice Menu. In it you will have 3 options to choose, You can navigate through the slide up or down after hearing the chosen option, make a double-tap to proceed.</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_2">Voice speed 1</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_3">Voice speed 2</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_4">Voice speed 3</string>

    //string tutorial main menu
    <string name="tutorial_1">You are in the environment screen here you learn how to use the navigation mechanisms within the application to return to the previous menu, just make an L in reverse at any time to begin, you must use the application menus. is very simple, just slide your finger anywhere on the screen and wait for the audio to return from the option where you find it. let\'s do it. slide your finger anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_2">To navigate between options, swipe up or down</string>
    <string name="tutorial_3">To confirm a chosen move or option, double-tap simultaneously</string>
    <string name="tutorial_4">To return to the previous screen, perform the movement of L in reverse</string>
    <string name="tutorial_5">To request help on the issue resolution screen, press and hold anywhere on the screen for 2 seconds</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6">To stop the audio, bring your hand in front of your smartphone screen</string>

    //string conceitos
    <string name="conceito_1">Gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_2">Genotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_3">Phenotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_4">Heterozygote</string>
    <string name="conceito_5">Homozygous</string>
    <string name="conceito_6">Dominant</string>
    <string name="conceito_7">Recessive</string>
    <string name="conceito_8">Codominance</string>
    <string name="conceito_9">Allele</string>
    <string name="conceito_10">Gametes</string>
    <string name="conceito_11">Dihybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_12">Monohybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_13">You are in the concept screen to navigate through them just swipe up or down, to return to the menu, make an reverse  L anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="conceito_14">Gene, Are specific sequences of nucleotides in DNA that constitute the fundamental unit of heredity.</string>
    <string name="conceito_15">Genotype, Group of genes of the individual.</string>
    <string name="conceito_16">Phenotype, Group of physical and physiological characteristics of an individual that results of the expression of the model and action of the environment.</string>
    <string name="conceito_17">Heterozygote, When an individual has two different alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_18">Homozygous, When an individual has two equal alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_19">Dominant, The allele is expressed in a homozygous condition and in a heterozygous condition</string>
    <string name="conceito_20">Recessive, The allele is only expressed in homozygosis for that reason it has no phenotypic effect when in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_21">Codominance, Situation in which the expression of the phenotypes of both alleles is observed when presented in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_22">Allele, alternative form of a gene that affects the same characteristic differently.</string>
    <string name="conceito_23">Gametes, are cells involved in sexual reproduction Heredity: transmission of resources from parents to their descendants.</string>
    <string name="conceito_24">Dihybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s second law, where differences in one characteristic are inherited regardless of differences in another characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_25">Monohybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s first law, and applies to hybrid individuals, considering only one characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_0">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>




</resources>
