<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BIOBLU - BIOLOGY TEACHER FOR BLIND USERS</string>

    //string da classe main
    <string name="main_menu_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="main_menu_2">MENDEL\'S 1ST LAW</string>
    <string name="main_menu_3">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="main_menu_4">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>
    <string name="main_menu_5">Welcome to BIOBLU you are on the main menu. To navigate through options swipe up or down. A double tap allows you to choose an option.</string>
    <string name="main_menu_6">If you want to close the BIOBLU App Press and hold on the screen for two seconds. If you don\'t want to close, slide up or down to continue browsing!</string>
    <string name="main_menu_7">"Wrong Move"</string>
    <string name="main_menu_8">MENDEL\'S 2ST LAW</string>
    <string name="main_menu_9">MULTIPLE ALLELES</string>

    //string da classe voice rate
    <string name="congifuracao_0">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_1">This is the Voice Speed Choice Menu. In it you will have 3 options to choose, You can navigate through the slide up or down after hearing the chosen option, make a double-tap to proceed.</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_2">Voice speed 1</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_3">Voice speed 2</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_4">Voice speed 3</string>

    //string tutorial main menu
    <string name="tutorial_1">You are in the environment screen here you learn how to use the navigation mechanisms within the application to return to the previous menu, just make an L in reverse at any time to begin, you must use the application menus. is very simple, just slide your finger anywhere on the screen and wait for the audio to return from the option where you find it. let\'s do it. slide your finger anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_2">To navigate between options, swipe up or down</string>
    <string name="tutorial_3">To confirm a chosen move or option, double-tap simultaneously</string>
    <string name="tutorial_4">To return to the previous screen, perform the movement of L in reverse</string>
    <string name="tutorial_5">To request help on the issue resolution screen, press and hold anywhere on the screen for 2 seconds</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6">To stop the audio, bring your hand in front of your smartphone screen</string>

    //string conceitos
    <string name="conceito_1">Gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_2">Genotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_3">Phenotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_4">Heterozygote</string>
    <string name="conceito_5">Homozygous</string>
    <string name="conceito_6">Dominant</string>
    <string name="conceito_7">Recessive</string>
    <string name="conceito_8">Codominance</string>
    <string name="conceito_9">Allele</string>
    <string name="conceito_10">Gametes</string>
    <string name="conceito_11">Dihybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_12">Monohybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_13">You are in the concept screen to navigate through them just swipe up or down, to return to the menu, make an reverse  L anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="conceito_14">Gene, Are specific sequences of nucleotides in DNA that constitute the fundamental unit of heredity.</string>
    <string name="conceito_15">Genotype, Group of genes of the individual.</string>
    <string name="conceito_16">Phenotype, Group of physical and physiological characteristics of an individual that results of the expression of the model and action of the environment.</string>
    <string name="conceito_17">Heterozygote, When an individual has two different alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_18">Homozygous, When an individual has two equal alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_19">Dominant, The allele is expressed in a homozygous condition and in a heterozygous condition</string>
    <string name="conceito_20">Recessive, The allele is only expressed in homozygosis for that reason it has no phenotypic effect when in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_21">Codominance, Situation in which the expression of the phenotypes of both alleles is observed when presented in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_22">Allele, alternative form of a gene that affects the same characteristic differently.</string>
    <string name="conceito_23">Gametes, are cells involved in sexual reproduction Heredity: transmission of resources from parents to their descendants.</string>
    <string name="conceito_24">Dihybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s second law, where differences in one characteristic are inherited regardless of differences in another characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_25">Monohybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s first law, and applies to hybrid individuals, considering only one characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_0">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>

    //string da classe cruzamento
    <string name="cruzamento_1">Now you are in the crossing screen. Make 4 taps to inform the Application which crossing you will make. After that, swipe 8 times to make the crossing you informed above</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_2">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_3">Gene </string>
    <string name="cruzamento_4">Homozygous Dominant Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_5">Heterozygous Dominant Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_6">Homozygous Recessive Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_7">You got it right !!! Continue.</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_8">The Genes generated through the Crossings were</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_9">Homozygote Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_10">Heterozygous Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_11">Homozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_12">Heterozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_13">Homozygote Recessive Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_14">Dominant</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_15">Recessive</string>

    //string da classe erro
    <string name="erro_1">BACK TO MENU</string>
    <string name="erro_2">Sorry, but we could not find any questions with your ID or you are not connected to the internet. To return to the menu, navigate to the option return to the menu and select</string>

    //string da classe seleção de letra
    <string name="selecao_0">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="selecao_1">You are  at Letter selection screen for the crossing. after choosing the desired option with the swipe up or down, double-tap to select the letter.</string>
    <string name="selecao_2">A</string>
    <string name="selecao_3">D</string>
    <string name="selecao_4">V</string>

    //string da classe select questão
    <string name="select_questao_0">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="select_questao_00">You are in the question selection screen. after choosing the desired option with the swipe up or down, double-tap to select the question</string>
    <string name="select_questao_1">Question 1</string>
    <string name="select_questao_2">Question 2</string>
    <string name="select_questao_3">Question 3</string>
    <string name="select_questao_4">Question 4</string>
    <string name="select_questao_5">Question 5</string>
    <string name="select_questao_6">We know that albinism is a recessive genetic anomaly in which the individual has a deficiency in the production of melanin in their skin, If a boy who produces melanin normally, but has a brother who is albine, ( Heterozygous Dominant), marries an albino girl, (Homozygous Recessive), What is the cross between this couple? </string>
    <string name="select_questao_7">Since myopia is considered a recessive disease, determine the crossing of a normal heterozygous couple for myopia</string>
    <string name="select_questao_8">What is the crossing generated by a couple, that both are heterozygous?</string>
    <string name="select_questao_9">A man who has dark eyes but with a mother with light eyes, married a woman with light eyes whose father has dark-eyed parents. Determine this crossing</string>
    <string name="select_questao_10">Achondroplasia is a type of dwarfism in which the head and trunk are normal, but the arms and legs are very short, It is conditioned by a dominant gene that, in homozygosity, causes death before birth. Normal individuals are recessive and the affected ones are heterozygous. What is this crossing?</string>
    //string da classe menu
    <string name="menu_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="menu_2">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="menu_3">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_4">SEARCH QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_5">You are on the Mendels first law module. you can choose the desired option by sliding on the screen</string>
    <string name="menu_6">MENDEL LAW</string>

    //string da classe Questao
    <string name="questao_1">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="questao_2">Dominant Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="questao_3">Domimant Heterozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="questao_4">Recessive Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="questao_5">You got it right !!! Continue</string>
    <string name="questao_6">The Homozygous Dominant Informed Gene is wrong, please try again</string>
    <string name="questao_7">The Heterozygous Dominant Informed Gene is wrong, please try again</string>
    <string name="questao_8">The Homozygous Recessive Informed Gene is wrong, please try again</string>
    <string name="questao_9">The Crossing is Correct. The Genes generated through the Crossings were</string>
    <string name="questao_10">Homozygote Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="questao_11">Heterozygous Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="questao_12">Homozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="questao_13">Heterozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="questao_14">Homozygote Recessive Percent</string>
    <string name="questao_15">to return to the menu, make an reverse  L in any part of the screen</string>
    <string name="questao_16">The dominant gene is the one that determines a characteristic, and the recessive is only expressed when duplicated, thats explained because when there is a dominant it becomes inactive</string>
    <string name="questao_17">We know that albinism is a recessive genetic anomaly in which the individual shows a deficiency in the production of melanin in his skin If a boy who produces melanin normally, but has a brother who is albino, (Heterozygous Dominant), marries an albino girl, (Homozygous Recessive), What is the cross between this couple? </string>
    <string name="questao_18">Since the couple is heterozygous and myopia has recessive characteristics, we know that their allele is present in the two pairs of chromosomes</string>
    <string name="questao_19">Given that myopia is considered a recessive disease determine the cross between  a normal heterozygous couple for myopia</string>
    <string name="questao_20">Heterozygotes represent individuals with different allele genes, one dominant and one recessive</string>
    <string name="questao_21">What is the crossing generated by a couple, that both are heterozygous?</string>
    <string name="questao_22">The color of dark eyes is dominant over light eyes, which is recessive</string>
    <string name="questao_23">a man who has dark eyes but with a mother with light eyes, married a woman with light eyes whose father has dark-eyed parents. Determine this crossings</string>
    <string name="questao_24">if the gene has dominant homozygous characteristics, the fetus dies, if it is dominant heterozygote, the child is born with the genetic condition</string>
    <string name="questao_25">The achondroplasia is a type of dwarfism in which the head and body are normal, but the arms and legs are too short It is conditioned by a dominant gene that in homozygous causes death before birth Normal individuals are recessive and the affected individuals are heterozygous. What is this crossing?</string>
    <string name="questao_26">Gene A Dominant, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="questao_27">Gene A Recessive, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="questao_28">Dominant</string>
    <string name="questao_29">Recessive</string>

    //string da Serch question
    <string name="search_question_1">SEARCH QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="search_question_2">You are on the search screen for Mendels first law. To search for the questions , simple swipe down or swipe up the screen after hearing the question command, double-tap to select</string>
    <string name="search_question_3">QUESTIONS</string>

    //string da classe solve and send
    <string name="solve_and_send_1">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_2">Dominate Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_3"> Dominate Heterozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_4"> Recessive Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_5">Gene </string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_6">Dominant, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_7">Dominant</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_8">To send a reply click and hold on the screen, to return to the menu do an L in reverse</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_9"> recessive, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_10"> recessive</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_11">The solution was sent successfully!</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_12">There was an error submitting the solution, please try again!</string>

    //string tutorial 1 law
    <string name="tutorial_1law">This is the tutorial screen of the first law of Mendel, here you will learn how to use the resolution mechanisms used in the application for the first law" +
            "             To start, we will make the following crossing what is the result of crossing pure yellow seed peas with pure green seed peas" +
            "             to start we will inform the parental genes. now swipe up or down on the left side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_dominante">Dominant V gene, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="tutorial_recessivo">Recessive v gene, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="tutorial_4law">You must swipe up or down on the right side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_5law">You must swipe up or down on the left side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6law">Make an reverse  “L” to go to the menu</string>
    <string name="tutorial_7law">Enter one more parental gene by swiping up or down on the left side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_8law">Dominant Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="tutorial_9law">Recessive Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="tutorial_11law">"You entered the first pair. now swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_12law">"you're doing well. enter another parental gene by swiping up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_13law">"great, now you will report the results of the f1 generation. to do this swipe up or down on the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_14law">"Enter the second gene on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_15law">"very well. inform the other F1 generation gene by swiping up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>

    <string name="tutorial_16law">"perfect. enter the second gene of generation f1 on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_17law">"very well, you informed the genes of the parental generation f1. now inform the result of the generation F2. to start slide on the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_18law">"Swipe up or down on the left side of the screen "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_19law">"Swipe up or down one more time on the left side of the screen "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_20law">"Great!, Now swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_21law">"Perfect!, Now swipe up or down on the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_22law">"you're doing well. Swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_23law">"Swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_24law">"Very Good! Swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_25law">"You have completed the question and finished the setting successfully, to proceed make an reverse  “L” on any part of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_26law">"You asked for help: every time you need help, just press the screen for two seconds"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_27law">Let\'s practice!</string>

    //segunda lei ----------------------------------------------------

    //string menu 2 lei
    <string name="menu_2lei_0">MELDEL´S LAW</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_2">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_3">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_4">SEARCH QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_5">You are in the module of the 2nd law of Mendel. you can navigate between the options by swiping up or down, after hearing the chosen option, double tap to proceed</string>

    //string menu polialelia
    <string name="polialelia1">MULTIPLE ALLELES</string>
    <string name="polialelia2">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="polialelia3">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="polialelia4">You are in the multiple alleles module, you can choose the desired option by sliding your finger on the screen.</string>

    //string select gene polialelia
    <string name="select_polialelia1">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia2">C</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia3">Ch</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia4">Cch</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia5">Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia8">Dominance: C> Cch> Ch> Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia9">Genotype</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia10">CC, C Cch, C Ch and C Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia11">CchCch, CchCh and CchCa</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia12">ChCh and Ch Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia13">CaCa</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia14">Phenotype</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia15">Wild or Aguti</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia16">chinchilla</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia17">Himalaya</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia18">Albino</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia19">Wild</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia20">Chinchilla</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia21">Himalaia</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia22">Albino</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia23">you\'re on the screen for choosing polyalelia genes. you must select 4 alleles, where the first two will refer to the first rabbit, and the last two to the second rabbit. after that you will be redirected to the crossing screen</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia24">Gene confirmed </string>

    //string cruzamento 2 lei
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_1">You are in the crossing screen, in the previous screen the f1 generation genes were informed, now inform the f2 generation genes</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_2">Gene</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_3">dominant, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_4">dominant</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_5">recessive, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_6">recessive</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_7">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_8">Dominant homozygote</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_9">Heterozygous</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_10">Recessive homozygote</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_11">"Enter the second gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_12">"Enter the third gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_13">"Enter the fourth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_14">"Enter the fifth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_15">"Enter the sixth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_16">"Enter the seventh gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_17">"Enter the last gene of the f2 generation"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_18">“Perfect, you are going to popularize the Punnett chart according to the results of the F2 generation. After informing the first two results we will check if it is correct, if it continues, if it is not correct, we will repeat the process. Remember, the graph must be completed with the f2 generation genes, come on, tell us the first gene</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_19">"perfect, tell the second gene"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_20">"perfect, enter the third gene"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_21">"perfect, tell the fourth gene"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_22">"very well, now inform the first gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_23">"great, now enter the second gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_24">"great, now enter the third gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_25">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_26">"very well, now we will check the reported results."</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_27">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct, now we will inform the other two pairs, inform the first gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_28">"the reported result is incorrect, repeat again"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_29">"perfect, tell the second gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_30">"perfect, tell the third gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_31">"perfect, tell the fourth gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_32">"very well, now enter the first gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_33">"great, now enter the second gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_34">"great, now enter the third gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_35">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_36">"very well, now we will check the reported results."</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_37">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct. as the process of filling in is very time consuming and we have learned, we will complete the picture for you. to do this, just double-tap the screen"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_38"> "the reported result is incorrect, repeat again"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_39"> From that moment you can navigate within the frame by touching the screen "+ '\ n' +" upwards you increase the column index, making it move through the elements line by line, when you reach the end of the line will move on to the next "
                                 + '\ n' + "down you decrease the column index, doing the opposite behavior to the previous one."</string>

    //string classe cruzamento coelho
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho1">"on the previous screen you entered the parental alleles, now perform this crossing!"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho2">"Gene confirmed"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho3">"Wild "</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho4">"Chinchilla"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho5">Himalaya</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho6">Albinho</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho7">"The Homozygous Informed Gene Dominate is wrong, try again."</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho8">"The Homozygous Informed Gene Dominate is wrong, try again."</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho9">"The Homozygous Informed Gene Dominate is wrong, try again."</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho10">"The Homozygous Informed Gene Dominate is wrong, try again."</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho11">"The Genes generated through Crossbreeding were,"</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho12">Wild Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho13">Percent Chinchilla</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho14">Himalayan Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho15">Percent albino</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho16">Wild percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho17">Percent chinchilla and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho18">himalayan percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho19">"Gene,"</string>

    //string questão coelho
    <string name="questao2_1">"Gene"</string>
    <string name="questao2_2">"dominant, double tap to confirm"</string>
    <string name="questao2_3">dominant</string>
    <string name="questao2_4">"recessive, double tap to confirm"</string>
    <string name="questao2_5">recessive</string>
    <string name="questao2_6">"item:"</string>
    <string name="questao2_7">"Gene confirmed"</string>
    <string name="questao2_8">"Enter the second gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="questao2_9">"Dominant Homozygote"</string>
    <string name="questao2_10">"Heterozygote"</string>
    <string name="questao2_11">"Recessive homozygote"</string>
    <string name="questao2_12">"Enter the third gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="questao2_13">"Enter the fourth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="questao2_14">"Enter the fifth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="questao2_15">"Enter the sixth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="questao2_16">"Enter the seventh gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="questao2_17">"Enter the last gene of the f2 generation"</string>
    <string name="questao2_18">"Perfect, you are going to populate the Punnett chart according to the results of the F2 generation. After informing each allele we will verify that it is correct, if it is continued, if it is not correct, we will repeat the process. Remembering, the chart must be filled with f2 generation genes, come on, tell us the first gene "</string>
    <string name="questao2_19">"perfect, tell the second gene"</string>
    <string name="questao2_20">"perfect, enter the third gene"</string>
    <string name="questao2_21">"perfect, tell the fourth gene"</string>
    <string name="questao2_22">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct, now we will inform the next pair, inform the first gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_23">"the reported result is incorrect, repeat the genes of the first allele again"</string>
    <string name="questao2_24">"great, now enter the second gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_25">"great, now enter the third gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_26">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_27">"very well, now we will check the reported results."</string>
    <string name="questao2_28">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct, now we will inform the next pair, inform the first gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_29">"the reported result is incorrect, repeat the second allele genes again"</string>
    <string name="questao2_30">"perfect, tell the second gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_31">"perfect, tell the third gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_32">"perfect, tell the fourth gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_33">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct, now we will inform the next pair, inform the first gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_34">"the reported result is incorrect, repeat the third allele genes again"</string>
    <string name="questao2_35">"great, now enter the second gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_36">"great, now enter the third gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_37">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="questao2_38">"very well, now we will check the reported results."</string>
    <string name="questao2_39">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct. as the process of filling in is very time consuming and we saw that you learned, we will complete the picture for you. to do this, just double-tap the screen"</string>
    <string name="questao2_40">"the reported result is incorrect, repeat the genes of the fourth allele again"</string>
    <string name="questao2_41">From that moment you can navigate within the frame by touching the screen "+ '\ n' +" upwards you increase the index of the column, making it move in the elements line by line, when you reach the end of the line it will move to next "
                                 + '\ n' + "down you decrease the column index, doing the opposite behavior to the previous one</string>

    //string classe search questão 2 law
    <string name="search2law_3">QUESTION 1</string>
    <string name="search2law_4">QUESTION 2</string>
    <string name="search2law_5">QUESTION 3</string>
    <string name="search2law_6">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="search2law_7">"You are at the question selection screen. After choosing the desired option with the swipe up or down, double-tap to select the question"</string>
    <string name="search2law_11">"In poultry, the C gene conditions white plumage and its recessive allele, Color plumage. The P gene determines paws with feathers and its recessive allele, paws without feathers. These pairs of genes are autosomal and segregate independently. One white bird with feathered legs, homozygous for the two pairs of genes, was crossed with a colored bird with featherless legs. If the obitted offspring are crossed, which genes will be generated?. The genes parents were informed, inform the genes of generation F2 "</string>
    <string name="search2law_12">"In rabbits, the P gene produces black fur and its recessive allele p, brown fur as long as the A gene is present. The aa animals are always albino. Considering that there is independent segregation between these genes, from the double heterozygous cross with a double recessive, which were the genes generated. The parental genes were informed, inform the genes of generation F2 "</string>
    <string name="search2law_13">"Normal hearing depends on the presence of at least one dominant of two pairs of genes, D and E, which segregate independently. If you examine the offspring of a large number of marriages in which both spouses are doubles heterozygous for these two pairs of genes, what are the genes generated. Parental genes have been informed, inform the genes of generation F2 "</string>


    //string select letra 2law
    <string name="select_letra2law_1">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_2">"You are in the second law selection screen for genes. To navigate between them just swipe up or down.
                             you will have three options on each side of the screen, slide on one side at a time. after reaching the desired option, double-tap to select.
                             to return to the menu, make a reverse L anywhere on the screen "</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_3">"Dominant Homozygote A"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_4">"Selected Homozygous Dominant A"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_5">"Dominant Heterozygote A"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_6">"Selected Heterozygote Dominant A"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_7">"Recessive Homozygote A"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_8">"Selected Homozygous Recessive A"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_9">"Dominant Homozygote B"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_10">"Selected Homozygous Dominant B"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_11">"Dominant heterozygote B"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_12">"Selected Heterozygote Dominant B"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_13">"Recessive Homozygote B"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_14">"Selected Recessive Homozygote B"</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_01">AA</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_02">Aa</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_03">aa</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_04">BB</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_05">Bb</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_06">bb</string>

    //tring da classe search question
    <string name="search2law_1_1">"You are in the search screen of the second law of mendel, to search for questions just slide up and down on the screen after hearing the command of the question, double-tap to select"</string>
    <string name="search2law_2_2">"QUESTION"</string>
    <string name="search2law_3_3">SEARCH QUESTIONS</string>

    //string da classe solve and send question
    <string name="solve_and_send1">"based on the data in the question, inform the genes of generation f1"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send2">"Gene"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send3">"dominant double-tap to confirm"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send4">"recessive double tap to confirm"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send5">"Gene confirmed"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send6">"Enter the second gene of generation f1"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send7">"Enter the third gene of generation f1"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send8">"Enter the fourth gene of generation f1"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send9">"Okay, report the first gene of the F2 generation"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send10">"Enter the second gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send11">"Dominant Homozygote"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send12">"Heterozygote"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send13">"Recessive homozygote"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send14">"Enter the third gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send15">"Enter the fourth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send16">"Enter the fifth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send17">"Enter the sixth gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send18">"Enter the seventh gene of generation f2"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send19">"Enter the last gene of the f2 generation"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send20">"Perfect, you are going to popularize the Punnett chart according to the results of the F2 generation. Remembering, the chart must be filled with the genes of the f2 generation, come on, tell us the first gene"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send21">"perfect, tell the second gene"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send22">"perfect, enter the third gene"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send23">"perfect, tell the fourth gene"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send24">"very well, now inform the first gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send25">"great, now enter the second gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send26">"great, now enter the third gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send27">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send28">"very well, now inform the first gene of the third allele."</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send29">"perfect, tell the second gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send30">"perfect, tell the third gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send31">"perfect, tell the fourth gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send32">"very well, now enter the first gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send33">"great, now enter the second gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send34">"great, now enter the third gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send35">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send36">"perfect, as the filling process takes a long time and we saw that you’ve learned, we’ll complete the picture for you. just double tap the screen"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send37">"To submit your answer, click and hold the screen for 2 seconds"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send38">"The solution was sent successfully!"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send39">"There was an error submitting the solution, please try again!"</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send40">"to hear the result obtained, just slide up or down to navigate between items. if you want to return to the menu, make an L in reverse"</string>

    //string classe tutorial 2 law
    <string name="tutorial2law_1">"You are at the second law tutorial screen. To learn how to use the mechanism of the second law module, we will do the following:
                             we will cross between smooth and yellow seeds with rough and green seeds.
                             where the uppercase V gene is dominant and represents the characteristic of the yellow color, the lowercase v gene is recessive and has the characteristic of the smooth pea, the dominant R gene.
                             to start, enter the first gene of the parental generation by sliding upwards on the left part of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_2">V</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_3">Gene</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_4">"Dominant V"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_5">"double tap to confirm"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_6">"You must touch the bottom of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_7">"You must touch the other side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_8">"R"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_9">Dominant R</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_10">"You must touch the top of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_11">"You must touch the other side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_12">"v"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_13">"V recessive"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_14">"r"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_15">"r recessive"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_16">"Gene confirmed"</string>

    <string name="tutorial2law_17">"Enter the second gene of the parental generation by touching the upper left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_18">"Enter the third gene of the parental generation by touching the bottom left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_19">"Enter the fourth gene of the parental generation by touching the bottom left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_20">"Enter the fifth gene of the parental generation by touching the upper right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_21">"Enter the sixth gene of the parental generation by touching the upper right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_22">"Enter the seventh gene of the parental generation by touching the bottom right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_23">"Enter the eighth gene of the parental generation by touching the lower right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_24">"Very well, now we will inform the genes of generation f1. To start inform the first gene in the upper left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_25">"Enter the second gene of generation f1 by touching the upper right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_26">"Enter the third gene of generation f1 by touching the bottom left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_27">"Enter the last gene of the f1 generation by touching the lower left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_28">"Perfect, now we will inform the elements of the F2 generation. To start, touch the top left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_29">"Enter the second gene of the f2 generation by touching the bottom left corner of the screen"</string>

    <string name="tutorial2law_30">"Dominant Homozygote"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_31">"Heterozygote"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_32">"Recessive homozygote"</string>

    <string name="tutorial2law_33">"Enter the third gene of the f2 generation by touching the upper left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_34">"Enter the fourth gene of the f2 generation by touching the lower right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_35">"Enter the fifth gene of the f2 generation by touching the lower right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_36">"Enter the sixth gene of the f2 generation by touching the bottom left corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_37">"Enter the seventh gene of the f2 generation by touching the upper right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_38">"Enter the last gene of the f2 generation by touching the lower right corner of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_39">"Perfect, you are going to populate the Punnett chart according to the results of the F2 generation. After informing each allele we will verify that it is correct, if it is continued, if it is not correct, we will repeat the process. Remembering, the chart must be filled with f2 generation genes, come on, tell us the first gene "</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_40">"perfect, tell the second gene"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_41">"perfect, enter the third gene"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_42">"perfect, tell the fourth gene"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_43">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct, now we will inform the next pair, inform the first gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_44">"the reported result is incorrect, repeat the genes of the first allele again"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_45">"great, now enter the second gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_46">"great, now enter the third gene from the second allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_47">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the second allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_48">"very well, now we will check the reported results."</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_49">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct, now we will inform the next pair, inform the first gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_50">"perfect, tell the second gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_51">"perfect, tell the third gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_52">"perfect, tell the fourth gene of the third allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_53">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct, now we will inform the next pair, inform the first gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_54">"great, now enter the second gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_55">"great, now enter the third gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_56">"great, now enter the fourth gene of the fourth allele"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_57">"very well, now we will check the reported results."</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_58">"perfect, the results reported so far are correct. as the process of filling in is very time consuming and we saw that you learned, we will complete the picture for you. to do this, just double-tap the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial2law_59">"From that moment on, you can navigate within the frame by touching the screen. Upwards you increase the column index, making it move in the elements line by line, when you reach the end of the line you will move to the next"
                                 down you decrease the column index, doing the opposite behavior to the previous one. if you want to return to the menu make an L in reverse "</string>

    //string tutorial polialelia
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_0">Let\'s practice!</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_1">"This is the tutorial screen for the polyalelia module. Here you will learn how to use the resolution mechanisms used in the application for questions regarding polyalelia.
             To begin we will make the following crossing. what is the result of crossing a wild rabbit with himalayan recessivity, with a chinchilla rabbit with albino recessivity
             to start we will inform the parental genes. now swipe up on the left side of the screen "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_2">"double tap to confirm"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_3">"Invalid touch, the reported gene is incorrect"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_4">"you finished the tutorial question, to return to the menu just make an L in reverse on any part of the screen."</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_5">"Wild Gene"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_6">"Himalayan gene"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_7">"Chinchilla gene"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_8">"Albino gene"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_9">"Enter one more parental gene by sliding down the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_10">"The first allele spawned a wild rabbit with Himalayan recessivity"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_11">"very well, now swipe up on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_12">"you are doing well. report one more parental gene by sliding down the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_13">"The second allele spawned a chinchilla rabbit with albino recessivity"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_14">"great, now you will report the results of the f2 generation. to do this, slide up the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_15">"Enter the second gene on the upper right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_16">"The first child is a wild rabbit with chinchilla recessivity"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_17">"very well. inform the other F2 gene by sliding up the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_18">"perfect. enter the fourth gene of generation f2 on the lower right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_19">"The second child is a wild rabbit with albino recessivity"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_20">"very well, slide up on the upper right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_21">"very well, beslize down the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_22">"The third child is a chinchilla rabbit with Himalayan recessivity"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_23">"Swipe down again on the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_24">"Great. Now slide down the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_25">"The fourth child is a Himalayan rabbit with albino recessivity"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_26">"perfect, you finished the tutorial question, to return to the menu just make an L in reverse on any part of the screen."</string>
    <string name="tutorial_poli2_27">"You asked for help: every time you need help, just hold the screen for two seconds"</string>




</resources>
