<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BIOBLU - BIOLOGY TEACHER FOR BLIND USERS</string>

    //string da classe main
    <string name="main_menu_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="main_menu_2">MENDEL\'S 1ST LAW</string>
    <string name="main_menu_3">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="main_menu_4">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>
    <string name="main_menu_5">Welcome to BIOBLU you are on the main menu. To navigate through options swipe up or down. A double tap allows you to choose an option.</string>
    <string name="main_menu_6">If you want to close the BIOBLU App Press and hold on the screen for two seconds. If you don\'t want to close, slide up or down to continue browsing!</string>
    <string name="main_menu_7">"Wrong Move"</string>
    <string name="main_menu_8">MENDEL\'S 2ST LAW</string>
    <string name="main_menu_9">MULTIPLE ALLELES</string>

    //string da classe voice rate
    <string name="congifuracao_0">CONFIGURATION</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_1">This is the Voice Speed Choice Menu. In it you will have 3 options to choose, You can navigate through the slide up or down after hearing the chosen option, make a double-tap to proceed.</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_2">Voice speed 1</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_3">Voice speed 2</string>
    <string name="congifuracao_4">Voice speed 3</string>

    //string tutorial main menu
    <string name="tutorial_1">You are in the environment screen here you learn how to use the navigation mechanisms within the application to return to the previous menu, just make an L in reverse at any time to begin, you must use the application menus. is very simple, just slide your finger anywhere on the screen and wait for the audio to return from the option where you find it. let\'s do it. slide your finger anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_2">To navigate between options, swipe up or down</string>
    <string name="tutorial_3">To confirm a chosen move or option, double-tap simultaneously</string>
    <string name="tutorial_4">To return to the previous screen, perform the movement of L in reverse</string>
    <string name="tutorial_5">To request help on the issue resolution screen, press and hold anywhere on the screen for 2 seconds</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6">To stop the audio, bring your hand in front of your smartphone screen</string>

    //string conceitos
    <string name="conceito_1">Gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_2">Genotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_3">Phenotype</string>
    <string name="conceito_4">Heterozygote</string>
    <string name="conceito_5">Homozygous</string>
    <string name="conceito_6">Dominant</string>
    <string name="conceito_7">Recessive</string>
    <string name="conceito_8">Codominance</string>
    <string name="conceito_9">Allele</string>
    <string name="conceito_10">Gametes</string>
    <string name="conceito_11">Dihybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_12">Monohybridisme</string>
    <string name="conceito_13">You are in the concept screen to navigate through them just swipe up or down, to return to the menu, make an reverse  L anywhere on the screen</string>
    <string name="conceito_14">Gene, Are specific sequences of nucleotides in DNA that constitute the fundamental unit of heredity.</string>
    <string name="conceito_15">Genotype, Group of genes of the individual.</string>
    <string name="conceito_16">Phenotype, Group of physical and physiological characteristics of an individual that results of the expression of the model and action of the environment.</string>
    <string name="conceito_17">Heterozygote, When an individual has two different alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_18">Homozygous, When an individual has two equal alleles of the same gene</string>
    <string name="conceito_19">Dominant, The allele is expressed in a homozygous condition and in a heterozygous condition</string>
    <string name="conceito_20">Recessive, The allele is only expressed in homozygosis for that reason it has no phenotypic effect when in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_21">Codominance, Situation in which the expression of the phenotypes of both alleles is observed when presented in heterozygosis</string>
    <string name="conceito_22">Allele, alternative form of a gene that affects the same characteristic differently.</string>
    <string name="conceito_23">Gametes, are cells involved in sexual reproduction Heredity: transmission of resources from parents to their descendants.</string>
    <string name="conceito_24">Dihybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s second law, where differences in one characteristic are inherited regardless of differences in another characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_25">Monohybridisme, this term refers to Mendel\'s first law, and applies to hybrid individuals, considering only one characteristic.</string>
    <string name="conceito_0">REVIEW CONCEPTS</string>

    //string da classe cruzamento
    <string name="cruzamento_1">Now you are in the crossing screen. Make 4 taps to inform the Application which crossing you will make. After that, swipe 8 times to make the crossing you informed above</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_2">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_3">Gene </string>
    <string name="cruzamento_4">Homozygous Dominant Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_5">Heterozygous Dominant Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_6">Homozygous Recessive Selected</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_7">You got it right !!! Continue.</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_8">The Genes generated through the Crossings were</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_9">Homozygote Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_10">Heterozygous Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_11">Homozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_12">Heterozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_13">Homozygote Recessive Percent</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_14">Dominant</string>
    <string name="cruzamento_15">Recessive</string>

    //string da classe erro
    <string name="erro_1">BACK TO MENU</string>
    <string name="erro_2">Sorry, but we could not find any questions with your ID or you are not connected to the internet. To return to the menu, navigate to the option return to the menu and select</string>

    //string da classe seleção de letra
    <string name="selecao_0">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="selecao_1">You are  at Letter selection screen for the crossing. after choosing the desired option with the swipe up or down, double-tap to select the letter.</string>
    <string name="selecao_2">A</string>
    <string name="selecao_3">D</string>
    <string name="selecao_4">V</string>

    //string da classe select questão
    <string name="select_questao_0">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="select_questao_00">You are in the question selection screen. after choosing the desired option with the swipe up or down, double-tap to select the question</string>
    <string name="select_questao_1">Question 1</string>
    <string name="select_questao_2">Question 2</string>
    <string name="select_questao_3">Question 3</string>
    <string name="select_questao_4">Question 4</string>
    <string name="select_questao_5">Question 5</string>
    <string name="select_questao_6">We know that albinism is a recessive genetic anomaly in which the individual has a deficiency in the production of melanin in their skin, If a boy who produces melanin normally, but has a brother who is albine, ( Heterozygous Dominant), marries an albino girl, (Homozygous Recessive), What is the cross between this couple? </string>
    <string name="select_questao_7">Since myopia is considered a recessive disease, determine the crossing of a normal heterozygous couple for myopia</string>
    <string name="select_questao_8">What is the crossing generated by a couple, that both are heterozygous?</string>
    <string name="select_questao_9">A man who has dark eyes but with a mother with light eyes, married a woman with light eyes whose father has dark-eyed parents. Determine this crossing</string>
    <string name="select_questao_10">Achondroplasia is a type of dwarfism in which the head and trunk are normal, but the arms and legs are very short, It is conditioned by a dominant gene that, in homozygosity, causes death before birth. Normal individuals are recessive and the affected ones are heterozygous. What is this crossing?</string>
    //string da classe menu
    <string name="menu_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="menu_2">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="menu_3">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_4">SEARCH QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_5">You are on the Mendels first law module. you can choose the desired option by sliding on the screen</string>
    <string name="menu_6">MENDEL LAW</string>

    //string da classe Questao
    <string name="questao_1">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="questao_2">Dominant Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="questao_3">Domimant Heterozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="questao_4">Recessive Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="questao_5">You got it right !!! Continue</string>
    <string name="questao_6">The Homozygous Dominant Informed Gene is wrong, please try again</string>
    <string name="questao_7">The Heterozygous Dominant Informed Gene is wrong, please try again</string>
    <string name="questao_8">The Homozygous Recessive Informed Gene is wrong, please try again</string>
    <string name="questao_9">The Crossing is Correct. The Genes generated through the Crossings were</string>
    <string name="questao_10">Homozygote Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="questao_11">Heterozygous Dominant Percent and</string>
    <string name="questao_12">Homozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="questao_13">Heterozygous Dominant Percent</string>
    <string name="questao_14">Homozygote Recessive Percent</string>
    <string name="questao_15">to return to the menu, make an reverse  L in any part of the screen</string>
    <string name="questao_16">The dominant gene is the one that determines a characteristic, and the recessive is only expressed when duplicated, thats explained because when there is a dominant it becomes inactive</string>
    <string name="questao_17">We know that albinism is a recessive genetic anomaly in which the individual shows a deficiency in the production of melanin in his skin If a boy who produces melanin normally, but has a brother who is albino, (Heterozygous Dominant), marries an albino girl, (Homozygous Recessive), What is the cross between this couple? </string>
    <string name="questao_18">Since the couple is heterozygous and myopia has recessive characteristics, we know that their allele is present in the two pairs of chromosomes</string>
    <string name="questao_19">Given that myopia is considered a recessive disease determine the cross between  a normal heterozygous couple for myopia</string>
    <string name="questao_20">Heterozygotes represent individuals with different allele genes, one dominant and one recessive</string>
    <string name="questao_21">What is the crossing generated by a couple, that both are heterozygous?</string>
    <string name="questao_22">The color of dark eyes is dominant over light eyes, which is recessive</string>
    <string name="questao_23">a man who has dark eyes but with a mother with light eyes, married a woman with light eyes whose father has dark-eyed parents. Determine this crossings</string>
    <string name="questao_24">if the gene has dominant homozygous characteristics, the fetus dies, if it is dominant heterozygote, the child is born with the genetic condition</string>
    <string name="questao_25">The achondroplasia is a type of dwarfism in which the head and body are normal, but the arms and legs are too short It is conditioned by a dominant gene that in homozygous causes death before birth Normal individuals are recessive and the affected individuals are heterozygous. What is this crossing?</string>
    <string name="questao_26">Gene A Dominant, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="questao_27">Gene A Recessive, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="questao_28">Dominant</string>
    <string name="questao_29">Recessive</string>

    //string da Serch question
    <string name="search_question_1">SEARCH QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="search_question_2">You are on the search screen for Mendels first law. To search for the questions , simple swipe down or swipe up the screen after hearing the question command, double-tap to select</string>
    <string name="search_question_3">QUESTIONS</string>

    //string da classe solve and send
    <string name="solve_and_send_1">Gene confirmed</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_2">Dominate Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_3"> Dominate Heterozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_4"> Recessive Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_5">Gene </string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_6">Dominant, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_7">Dominant</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_8">To send a reply click and hold on the screen, to return to the menu do an L in reverse</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_9"> recessive, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_10"> recessive</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_11">The solution was sent successfully!</string>
    <string name="solve_and_send_12">There was an error submitting the solution, please try again!</string>

    //string tutorial 1 law
    <string name="tutorial_1law">This is the tutorial screen of the first law of Mendel, here you will learn how to use the resolution mechanisms used in the application for the first law" +
            "             To start, we will make the following crossing what is the result of crossing pure yellow seed peas with pure green seed peas" +
            "             to start we will inform the parental genes. now swipe up or down on the left side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_dominante">Dominant V gene, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="tutorial_recessivo">Recessive v gene, double tap to confirm</string>
    <string name="tutorial_4law">You must swipe up or down on the right side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_5law">You must swipe up or down on the left side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6law">Make an reverse  “L” to go to the menu</string>
    <string name="tutorial_7law">Enter one more parental gene by swiping up or down on the left side of the screen</string>
    <string name="tutorial_8law">Dominant Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="tutorial_9law">Recessive Homozygous Gene</string>
    <string name="tutorial_11law">"You entered the first pair. now swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_12law">"you're doing well. enter another parental gene by swiping up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_13law">"great, now you will report the results of the f1 generation. to do this swipe up or down on the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_14law">"Enter the second gene on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_15law">"very well. inform the other F1 generation gene by swiping up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>

    <string name="tutorial_16law">"perfect. enter the second gene of generation f1 on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_17law">"very well, you informed the genes of the parental generation f1. now inform the result of the generation F2. to start slide on the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_18law">"Swipe up or down on the left side of the screen "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_19law">"Swipe up or down one more time on the left side of the screen "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_20law">"Great!, Now swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_21law">"Perfect!, Now swipe up or down on the left side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_22law">"you're doing well. Swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_23law">"Swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_24law">"Very Good! Swipe up or down on the right side of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_25law">"You have completed the question and finished the setting successfully, to proceed make an reverse  “L” on any part of the screen"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_26law">"You asked for help: every time you need help, just press the screen for two seconds"</string>
    <string name="tutorial_27law">Let\'s practice!</string>

    //segunda lei ----------------------------------------------------

    //string menu 2 lei
    <string name="menu_2lei_0">MELDEL´S LAW</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_1">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_2">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_3">QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_4">SEARCH QUESTIONS</string>
    <string name="menu_2lei_5">You are in the module of the 2nd law of Mendel. you can navigate between the options by swiping up or down, after hearing the chosen option, double tap to proceed</string>

    //string menu polialelia
    <string name="polialelia1">MULTIPLE ALLELES</string>
    <string name="polialelia2">TRAINING SCREEN</string>
    <string name="polialelia3">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="polialelia4">You are in the multiple alleles module, you can choose the desired option by sliding your finger on the screen.</string>

    //string select gene polialelia
    <string name="select_polialelia1">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia2">C</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia3">Ch</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia4">Cch</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia5">Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia8">Dominance: C> Cch> Ch> Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia9">Genotype</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia10">CC, C Cch, C Ch and C Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia11">CchCch, CchCh and CchCa</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia12">ChCh and Ch Ca</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia13">CaCa</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia14">Phenotype</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia15">Wild or Aguti</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia16">chinchilla</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia17">Himalaya</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia18">Albino</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia19">Wild</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia20">Chinchilla</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia21">Himalaia</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia22">Albino</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia23">you\'re on the screen for choosing polyalelia genes. you must select 4 alleles, where the first two will refer to the first rabbit, and the last two to the second rabbit. after that you will be redirected to the crossing screen</string>
    <string name="select_polialelia24">Gene confirmed </string>

    //string cruzamento 2 lei
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_1"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_2"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_3"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_4"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_5"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_6"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_7"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_8"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_9"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_10"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_11"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_12"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_13"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_14"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_15"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_16"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_17"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_18"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_19"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_20"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_21"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_22"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_23"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_24"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_25"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_26"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_27"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_28"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_29"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_30"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_31"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_32"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_33"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_34"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_35"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_36"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_37"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_38"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento2lei_39"></string>

    //string classe cruzamento coelho
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho1"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho2"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho3"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho4"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho5"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho6"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho7"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho8"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho9"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho10"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho11"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho12"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho13"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho14"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho15"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho16"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho17"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho18"></string>
    <string name="cruzamento_coelho19"></string>

    //string questão coelho
    <string name="questao2_1"></string>
    <string name="questao2_2"></string>
    <string name="questao2_3"></string>
    <string name="questao2_4"></string>
    <string name="questao2_5"></string>
    <string name="questao2_6"></string>
    <string name="questao2_7"></string>
    <string name="questao2_8"></string>
    <string name="questao2_9"></string>
    <string name="questao2_10"></string>
    <string name="questao2_11"></string>
    <string name="questao2_12"></string>
    <string name="questao2_13"></string>
    <string name="questao2_14"></string>
    <string name="questao2_15"></string>
    <string name="questao2_16"></string>
    <string name="questao2_17"></string>
    <string name="questao2_18"></string>
    <string name="questao2_19"></string>
    <string name="questao2_20"></string>
    <string name="questao2_21"></string>
    <string name="questao2_22"></string>
    <string name="questao2_23"></string>
    <string name="questao2_24"></string>
    <string name="questao2_25"></string>
    <string name="questao2_26"></string>
    <string name="questao2_27"></string>
    <string name="questao2_28"></string>
    <string name="questao2_29"></string>
    <string name="questao2_30"></string>
    <string name="questao2_31"></string>
    <string name="questao2_32"></string>
    <string name="questao2_33"></string>
    <string name="questao2_34"></string>
    <string name="questao2_35"></string>
    <string name="questao2_36"></string>
    <string name="questao2_37"></string>
    <string name="questao2_38"></string>
    <string name="questao2_39"></string>
    <string name="questao2_40"></string>
    <string name="questao2_41"></string>

    //string classe search question
    <string name="search2law_1"></string>
    <string name="search2law_2">Question</string>
    <string name="search2law_3">QUESTION 1</string>
    <string name="search2law_4">QUESTION 2</string>
    <string name="search2law_5">QUESTION 3</string>
    <string name="search2law_6"></string>
    <string name="search2law_7"></string>
    <string name="search2law_11"></string>
    <string name="search2law_12"></string>
    <string name="search2law_13"></string>

    //string select letra 2law
    <string name="select_letra2law_1">CROSSING</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_2"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_3"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_4"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_5"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_6"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_7"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_8"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_9"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_10"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_11"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_12"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_13"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_14"></string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_01">AA</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_02">Aa</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_03">aa</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_04">BB</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_05">Bb</string>
    <string name="select_letra2law_06">bb</string>


</resources>
